worldtravelawards.com 2018-10-20

# Privacy Policy – World Travel Awards

_Last Updated: 24 May 2018_

## 1\. Introduction

This Privacy Notice describes World Travel Awards ("we", "us", or "our") policies and practices regarding its collection and use of your personal data, and sets forth your privacy rights. It also describes your choices regarding use, access, correction and deletion of your personal information. We recognize that information privacy is an ongoing responsibility, and so we will from time to time update this Privacy Notice as we undertake new personal data practices or adopt new privacy policies.

## 2\. How we collect and use your personal information

We collect personal information about our voters (users), subscribers, nominees, event attendees, media contacts and other customers. We use this information to provide goods and services. We do not sell personal information to anyone and only share it with third parties you consent to or who are facilitating the delivery of our services.

### 2.1. Personal information you give to us:

#### 2.1.1. Voters (Users)

To avoid fraudulent votes we do require that users register before voting. When you register as a user to vote, we collect information about you including (but not limited to) your name, your country location and your email address. An email will be sent to you to verify your email address and activate your account. Unverified accounts will receive a reminder email before being deleted.

If you work in the travel & tourism industry you may upgrade your account to Industry Status by providing your employer's name and website, your job title and industry classification. If you work for one of our nominees, we may contact you about your nomination.

During registration you may opt-in our mailing lists including our media partner Breaking Travel News's daily industry news mailing list. If you opt-in to this third-party mailing list your email address will be shared with Breaking Travel News (once your account is activated) in order for them to provide you with the service.

We collect your IP address during registration and voting which we use for detecting and combating fraudulent voting.

We process your personal information to provide you with a user account with which you can vote.

Users may edit their profile at any time to change, add, or remove personal information.

#### 2.1.2. Mailing List Subscribers

When you subscribe to our Newsletter, Partner and Best in Travel Magazine mailing lists we collect your email address and IP address and for our Media mailing list we ask you to supply contact information about who you represent. We require double opt-in to subscribe to our mailing lists and will send you an email with a link to verify your email address.

We use this information to send you the content you have subscribed to. You may unsubscribe at any time using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of every email or sending us a request to unsubscribe to [awards@worldtravelawards.com](mailto:awards@worldtravelawards.com).

#### 2.1.3. Nominees and entrants

We collect information from you when you submit an entry or contact us about your nomination. With a few exceptions, this information is limited to the kinds of information that can be found on a business card: first name, last name, employer name, work address, job title, work email and work phone numbers.

We use this information to process entries or orders and to notify you about your nomination.

#### 2.1.4. Events

We host award ceremonies. If you attend one of our events, we will collect your name and contact information, which we will store in our database and use to provide you with your ticket and services associated with the event.

We keep a record of your participation in our events.

Attendees may have photos and videos taken at the event which will be posted on the worldtravelawards.com website. Videos are hosted by YouTube.

Some of our events are sponsored. We may provide an attendee list to sponsors and/or co-sponsors of our events. Your email address is not included. If you do not wish to have your information included in an attendee list you may contact us directly at [awards@worldtravelawards.com](mailto:awards@worldtravelawards.com).

#### 2.1.5. Your correspondence with us

If you correspond with us by email, the postal service, or other form of communication, we may retain such correspondence and the information contained in it and use it to respond to your inquiry; to notify you of your nominations; or to keep a record of your complaint, request, and the like. As always, if you wish to have us "erase" your personal information or otherwise refrain from communicating with you, please contact us at [awards@worldtravelawards.com](mailto:awards@worldtravelawards.com).

Note: if you ask us not to contact you by email at a certain email address, we will retain a copy of that email address on its "master do not send" list in order to comply with your no-contact request.

#### 2.1.6. Payment card information

You may choose to purchase goods or services from us using a payment card. Typically, payment card information is provided directly by users, via our website, into the payment processing service to which we subscribe. Or users will be directed to make payment via our payment processing service's website. We do not process or store card information.

### 2.2. Personal information we get from third parties

We may receive personal information about individuals from third parties. This may happen if your employer or someone from your company provides your contact details as:

  * an attendee for an event.
  * a designated contact to receive notifications about your company's nomination/s.

### 2.3. Personal information we source

We may source personal information about individuals from your company website or by contacting your company. This may happen if your company is a nominee and we require a new contact at your company.

### 2.4. What happens if you don't give us your data

You can use our website without registering and much of the information on our website is available to non-users, however, to vote you will need to register.

## 3\. How can you edit your personal information?

Registered users may login and update the information available under My Account. For other information or other contacts, you may change your personal information at any time by emailing [awards@worldtravelawards.com](mailto:awards@worldtravelawards.com) and describing the changes you would like to make.

## 4\. Use of our website

As is true of most other websites, our website (www.worldtravelawards.com) collects certain information automatically and stores it in log files. The information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, the region or general location where your computer or device is accessing the internet, browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of our website, including a history of the pages you view. We use this information to help us design our site to better suit our users' needs. We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website, analyse trends, track visitor movements, and gather broad demographic information that assists us in identifying visitor preferences. Our website also uses cookies and web beacons.

### 4.1. Cookies and web beacons

Cookies are pieces of data that a Web site transfers to a user's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Web beacons are transparent pixel images that are used in collecting information about website usage, e-mail response and tracking.

The Site uses cookies and Web beacons to provide enhanced functionality on the site (e.g. registration and login) and aggregate traffic data (e.g., what pages are the most popular). These cookies may be delivered in a first-party or third-party context. We may also use cookies and web beacons in association with e-mails delivered by us. You have many choices with regards to the management of cookies on your computer. All major browsers allow you to block or delete cookies from your system. To learn more about your ability to manage cookies and web beacons, please consult the privacy features in your browser.

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purposes of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using our website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

For more information on our cookies or to adjust your cookie settings, visit our Cookie Policy page.

## 5\. When and how we share information with others

The personal information we collect from you is stored in one or more databases hosted by third party web hosting services located in the EU. These third parties do not use or have access to your personal information for any purpose other than storage and retrieval.

We do not otherwise reveal your personal data to third-parties for their independent use unless: (1) you request or authorise it; (2) the information is provided to comply with the law (for example, to comply with a search warrant, subpoena or court order), enforce an agreement we have with you, or to protect our rights, property or safety, or the rights, property or safety of our employees or others; (3) the information is provided to our agents, vendors or service providers who perform functions on our behalf; (4) to address emergencies or acts of God; or (5) to address disputes, claims, or to persons demonstrating legal authority to act on your behalf. We may also gather aggregated data about our users and Site visitors and disclose the results of such aggregated (but not personally identifiable) information to our partners, service providers and/or other third parties for marketing or promotional purposes.

Our website uses sharing tools with social media sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Google+ and others. If you choose to share information from our website through these services, you should review the privacy policy of that service. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your site visit to your personal data.

## 6\. Transferring personal data from the EU to the US

Our headquarters in the United Kingdom. Where permitted by applicable law, we may transfer your personal data to the United States and other jurisdictions outside the European Economic Area ('EEA') for the purposes of providing services as set out in this privacy policy.

## 7\. Data subject rights

The European Union's General Data Protection Regulation and other countries' privacy laws provide certain rights for data subjects. A good explanation of them (in English) is available on the website of the United Kingdom's [Information Commissioner's Office](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/data-protection-reform/overview-of-the-gdpr/individuals-rights/the-right-to-be-informed/).

This Privacy Notice is intended to provide you with information about what personal data we collect about you and how it is used. If you have any questions, please contact us at [awards@worldtravelawards.com](mailto:awards@worldtravelawards.com).

If you wish to confirm that we are processing your personal data, or to have access to the personal data we may have about you, please contact us at [awards@worldtravelawards.com](mailto:awards@worldtravelawards.com).

You may also request information about: the purpose of the processing; the categories of personal data concerned; who else outside our company might have received the data from us; what the source of the information was (if you didn't provide it directly to us); and how long it will be stored. You have a right to correct (rectify) the record of your personal data maintained by us if it is inaccurate. You may request that we erase that data or cease processing it, subject to certain exceptions. You may also request that we cease using your data for direct marketing purposes. In many countries, you have a right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate data protection authority if you have concerns about how we process your personal data. When technically feasible, we will—at your request—provide your personal data to you or transmit it directly to another controller.

Reasonable access to your personal data will be provided at no cost to our users, subscribers, customers and others upon request made to us at [awards@worldtravelawards.com](mailto:awards@worldtravelawards.com). If access cannot be provided within a reasonable time frame, we will provide you with a date when the information will be provided. If for some reason access is denied, we will provide an explanation as to why access has been denied.

## 8\. Website Links

Our Site contains links to and from the websites of third parties. Please note that if you follow a link to any of these websites, such websites will apply different terms to the collection and privacy of your personal data and we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. When you leave our Site, we encourage you to read the privacy notice/policy of every website you visit.

## 9\. Security of your information

We have implemented appropriate technical and organisational security measures designed to protect your Personal Data against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure, unauthorised access, and other unlawful or unauthorised forms of Processing, in accordance with applicable law.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

## 10\. Data storage, retention and erasure

Your personal data is stored by on our servers, hosted by third party web hosting services located in the EU. We retain data for the duration of the customer's or member's business relationship with us. If you no longer want us to use your information to provide services to you, you can withdraw your consent or request that we erase your information by contacting [awards@worldtravelawards.com](mailto:awards@worldtravelawards.com). Please note that if you request erasure of your information, we may retain some of your information as necessary for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud detection and prevention, and to comply with our legal obligations. We will respond to your request to exercise these rights within a reasonable time (and in all cases within 30 days of receiving a request).

## 11\. Safety of Minors

Our services are not intended for and may not be used by minors. "Minors" are individuals under the age of 13 (or under a higher age if permitted by the laws of their residence). We do not knowingly collect personal data from Minors or allow them to register. If it comes to our attention that we have collected personal information from a Minor, we may delete this information without notice. If you have reason to believe that this has occurred, please contact [awards@worldtravelawards.com](mailto:awards@worldtravelawards.com).

## 12\. Changes to our Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

## 13\. Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to:

World Media and Events Limited  
Berkeley Square House, Berkeley Square, London, W1J 6BD, United Kingdom  
+44 (0) 20 7925 0000
